世界上有俩处领域
...you see, you have two
realms in this world, you know,
玛雅的领域和神的领域
the realm of Maya
and the realm of the Divine.
所以 受限制的万物就是玛雅的世界
So, everything which is bound
by limitation is the world of Maya
包括头脑 智力 你的情感
which includes the mind,
the intellect, your emotions,
和你的身体 你的感官等等
you know, and your body,
your senses and so on.
它们都受到玛雅的限制 你有你的灵魂 它属于神
They are all bound by Maya. And then
you have your Atma which is Divine.
所以 你内在有这俩种
So, you have these
two inside of you.
有时你的灵魂正在提醒你生命中最重要的事情
Sometimes your Atma is reminding yourself,
you know, what is the most important thing in life
并且你有那强烈的感觉 但是你听从那吗 不 你不听从
and you have that deep feeling, but
do you listen to that? No, you don’t!
因为玛雅的世界已经极好地伪装了她自己
Because the world of Maya has
disguised Herself so wonderfully,
你知道的 如此诱人
you know,
so attractive,
如此令人着迷 如此快乐的以至于你认为 是的 我会很快乐
so mesmerising, so joyful that you
think that, "Yes, I will be happy."
并且很容易听从那个世界
And it’s easy to
listen to that world,
很容易朝向那 因为头脑和
it’s easy to divert towards
that, because that mind is
玛雅的相同的 它们以同一频率震动
the same as Maya, you know,
they vibrate in the same frequency.
所以 它是非常吸人引的
So, it’s very attractive.
所以 你更加的让自己 让那头脑被世界所吸引
So, more you let yourself – let that
mind be attracted to the world,
你陷入的更深
more you entangle into it.
那不意味着你的灵魂不会提醒你 它会的
It doesn’t mean that your
soul will not remind you. It will.
但有多少人真的跟随那
But how many people
really follow that?
很少 所以 这是俩个相对的世界
Very few. So, this is
two worlds of opposite,
你瞧 这些相对的俩个世界
you see, and these
two worlds of opposite:
薄伽梵奎师那提到过业瑜伽
Bhagavan Krishna talked
about the Karma Yoga,
智瑜伽和王瑜伽 不是吗
Jyaana Yoga and
Raja Yoga, no?
所以 存在着三种人 存在着三种内在的品质
So, these are three kinds of people that
exist, three qualities which exist inside.
但是祂也说过神性
But He talked
also the divine
不受任何东西限制
qualities which are
not bound by anything.
所以 你的灵魂 它是什么
So, your Atma,
what it is?
玛雅的产物还是神的产物
Product of Maya
or product of God?
[神]
[God.]
所以 你的灵魂引领你到哪里 内在还是外在
So, where is your Atma leading
you? In the world or outside?
[外在 但同时也是内在]
[Outside, but at the
same time in the world.]
不 是你的头脑引领你到外在
No, it is your mind that
is leading you outside.
灵魂总是只有一个目标
Atma always
has only one aim.
灵魂不会有俩个目标 灵魂不会绑定于任何东西上
The Atma doesn’t have two aims. The
Atma is not attached to anything here.
是头脑绑定着一切
It is the mind that is
attached to everything.